# Parker Phelps

Winston-Salem, NC 27103 | 336-8313432 | pp101socials@gmail.com

## **Summary**

As a Front End Web Developer, I possess a wealth of experience and expertise in creating visually stunning and responsive user interfaces for websites and applications. With a deep understanding of web development technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, I have developed an extensive skill set in popular front-end frameworks such as React and Next.js.

# **Objective**

Recent graduate with an Associate's Degree in Web Technologies and Programming and Software Development. Currently seeking to leverage skills in coding (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Next.js, ReactJS), problem-solving, and communication to gain professional experience in a Front-End Developer role.

## **Skills**

- HTML5 (4 Years)
- CSS3 (4 Years)
- Responsive Design (4 Years)
- PowerPoint (4 Years)
- Word (4 Years)
- Excel (4 Years)
- ReactJS (3 Years)
- JavaScript (3 Years)
- SEO (2 Years)
- Bootstrap (2 Years)
- Sass/Scss (2 Years)
- Next.js (2 Years)
- PHP (2 Years)
- Git (2 Years)
- Scrum and Agile (2 Years)
- Java (2 Years)
- Photoshop (2 Years)
- Visual Basic (2 Years)

- Content Management System (CMS) (2 Years)
- .Net (2 Years)
- ASP.Net (2 Years)
- WordPress (2 Years)
- Adobe XD (2 Years)
- Python (2 Years)
- Swift (2 Years)
- UI/UX (2 Years)
- Illustrator (1 Year)
- Java Swing (1 Year)
- SQL (1 Year)
- Swing (1 Year)
- PyQt (1 Year)
- MongoDB (1 Year)
- SQLAlchemy (1 Year)
- Friendly, Positive Attitude
- Reliable and Trustworthy

## **Professional Experience**

RTSYVISUALS | 11/2021 - 1/2022

#### Freelance Consultant - Lexington, NC

#### https://rtsyvisuals.com

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript and ReactJS
- Paid for professional experience
- Hosting images/videos onto personal hosting server to provide faster loading times
- Single-handedly design a fully responsive layout for the whole website

#### **FIBERCOMPANY** | 06/2023 - 06/2023

#### Freelance Consultant - Winston-Salem, NC

#### www.fibercompanync.com

- Single-handedly created with WIX and EditorX
- Paid for professional experience
- Hosting images/videos onto personal hosting server to provide faster loading times
- Single-handedly design a fully responsive layout for the whole website

#### **ONLYJOJO** | 03/2022 - 04/2022

#### Freelance Consultant - Winston Salem, NC

https://startling-syrniki-d0dc90.netlify.app/

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Made into an ecommerce-type website with a shopping cart system that uses Session and Local Storage
- Applied features that relate to the manga and anime of the same name through the website

#### **A FRESH PLACE** | 01/2022 - 02/2022

#### Freelance Consultant - Winston-Salem, NC

https://effulgent-marshmallow-23dfdf.netlify.app/

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and ReactJS
- Developed the site to work with Microsoft Edge, Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome
- Made with a shopping cart system similar to OnlyJojo's

#### **SHARPQUILLS** | 12/2021 - 01/2022

#### Freelance Consultant - Winston-Salem, NC

https://astounding-gaufre-f9428d.netlify.app/

- Single-handedly created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Created custom modals for displaying images of the different hedgehogs
- Used text and information based on each individual hedgehog type

#### FLORA AND FAUNA | 09/2022 - 09/2022

#### Freelance Consultant - Winston-Salem, NC

https://fantastic-starburst-b0f940.netlify.app/

- Created with HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Next.js
- Single-handedly created an informational site dedicated to all the native flora and fauna in NC
- Used text and information based on each individual specimen

## **Education and Training**

Forsyth Technical Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Associate's

Programming and Software Development, 08/2020 – 05/2023

Forsyth Tech Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Associates

Web Technologies, 09/2018 - 05/2020

Forsyth Technical Community College - Winston-Salem, NC | Certificate

IT - Web Technology - Web Fundamentals, 03/2019

**CAPSTONE PROJECT** | 03/2023 - 05/2023

Forsyth Tech Community College – Winston-Salem, NC

https://aithub.com/mxrked/Medical-Office-Administration

- Worked with team of programmers and database technicians.
- Created the login, navigation and scheduling appointments window.
- Linked backend to Local database.

## Certifications

IT- Web Technology - Web Fundamentals March 2019

This certificate was gained when I was in Forsyth Tech Community College and took classes regarding the Web Fundamentals such as HTML5, CSS3.

## Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://codingthefront.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/parker-phelps-a121501b6/
- <a href="https://github.com/mxrked">https://github.com/mxrked</a>
- <a href="https://my.indeed.com/p/parkerp-lxyhsn9">https://my.indeed.com/p/parkerp-lxyhsn9</a>